Katherine Yuneman

Stamford, CT | 917-656-4580 | <u>kyuneman@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in **Ruby** and **JavaScript** based programming with a background in **Product Ownership/Management**. I possess strong skills in **cross-functional collaboration** and **communication** that help teams of any size work **quickly** and **efficiently**. I have a passion for **tinkering with problems** and testing to develop functional products from start to finish.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, React.is, HTML, CSS, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Agile Methodologies, GitHub, RESTful APIs

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Picky Baby - Github | Demo

User-friendly food and recipe database for babies starting solid food

- Built RESTful JSON API using Ruby on Rails to create a database to search for foods appropriate for babies
- Used Javascript and React is to display search results and connect foods with available recipes
- Used React and Ruby on Rails to allow for creation of new user recipes utilizing foods as ingredients

Borrow - Github | Demo

Book rental subscription app where user can add books to a cart each month

- Created Javascript and React is front-end app to display book inventory and history of user's rented books
- Utilized Redux to manage state of user and cart inventory
- Created back-end RESTful API using Ruby on Rails to manage inventory, condition of books, and rental status
- Combined Custom SQL with Active Record to join normalized tables of titles, authors, books, and book rentals

Budget Tracker - Github Front End | Github Back End | Demo

Budget Tracker manages money by adding a new monthly budget limit, individual transactions and budget progress.

- Utilized Sinatra API to store budget limits and transactions per month
- Created React front-end to display dashboard of budget progress and ability to add transactions

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Collab Lab
Collaborative Apprentice

Remote 04/2023 - Present

- Q2 2023 cohort working with a team of 3 other developers to create an accessible React.js single page web application connecting to a NoSQL Firebase cloud database
- Utilize GitHub for version control and implementing issues in an Agile environment in one-week sprints
- Participate in pair programming, writing pull requests, and doing code reviews

Banker's Healthcare Group / BHG Financial

New York, NY

Product Manager

02/2019 - 02/2021

- Managed project timelines and full development lifecycle, gathered requirements, implemented technical and nontechnical innovative strategies, performed Quality Assurance (QA) analysis, administered User Acceptance Testing (UAT), and monitored progress of strategy and product launches
- Partnered with technical teams remotely in Florida and Syracuse to ensure cohesive and fast-paced release management and seamless connection to Loan Origination System API
- Standardized Agile best practices and automated JIRA scrum board, created new documentation process for training

New York University

New York, NY

Senior Business Analyst - Global Data Administration

10/2010 - 02/2019

- Utilized Agile practices as project manager for implementing four streamlined web-based student applications for NYU New York, Abu Dhabi, and Shanghai within a three-month launch date remotely and on-site
- Managed product roadmap, wrote user stories, and evaluated business practices to improve service and operational
 efficiencies in reporting and creating transactions en masse using custom MS SQL Server scripts, SSIS packages
 and third-party vendor software

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Remote

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

11/2022

New York University

New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts - Economics and Journalism

05/2009